Listen to me.
OK, you win.
At least you could stop that song.
You know I hate it.
Why are you so quiet?
Say something!
You're there.
And you're looking at me.
Do you think you can fool me?
No, no, you can't fool me,
because I can feel your presence.
And your movements.
I can even smell you.
If you think...
If you think, son of a bitch,
that I'll hang myself
while you watch, you...
- What's wrong?
- What happened?
Julia, what's wrong?
Julia, can you hear me?
Bring some water.
Take it easy, Julia.
Julia, are you OK?
- What happened?
- She fell.
- Call a doctor, quick!
- No, I'm OK.
I'm OK.
This is Sara. I can't take your call
at the moment. Please...
Do you think it's a good idea
to show up after six months?
I just need to know
that she is all right.
Sara?
Maybe they have gone out.
No...
I know something's happened to her.
The power is out.
- The fuses seem to be OK.
- I'll look upstairs.
Sara?
Isaac, she's nowhere to be found.
We'll ask the neighbours.
- Don't come down.
- Why?
What's wrong?
Isaac, tell me what's wrong.
- What's wrong?
- Julia...
- Come with me.
Inspector...
I'm sorry about what happened.
No, thanks.
The forensics say Sara took her own life
last night, during the blackout.
But we need to find out why.
I have been informed that she suffered
a degenerative disease.
Yes, a progressive vision loss,
the same as my wife.
But Sara went blind a year ago.
And how did she cope with that?
My sister wasn't depressed,
if that's what you mean.
In fact, she was...
She was going to have surgery, right?
She was waiting for a donor,
but she hoped to get her vision back.
Maybe she got tired of waiting.
All right.
Yes, thank you.
Dr Román can't come to the funeral,
and he sends his condolences.
He also wants to check your eyes
before you go back home.
Isaac, the power is back.
Darling, are you listening?
And the CD started playing.
Did you hear it?
- Yes.
- Don't you think it's strange
that Sara was listening
to music before...?
Besides, she hated that song.
- Julia...
- What if she wasn't alone?
- What if she was with somebody?
- Julia, please.
We may never find out her reasons.
We hadn't heard from her in months.
It's strange.
I need to know what happened.
- It's not good for you to get upset.
- I'm not worried about myself.
Well, I am.
Stress can turn you blind.
It's only happened to me
twice in five years.
And you've lost 20% of your vision.
Oh, no... Again.
Did you find anything?
Nothing, not even a candle.
- It's time to meet the neighbours.
- OK, hurry up.
Isaac?
Julia.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I'm Blasco, her next-door neighbour.
I didn't know your sister very well,
but Lía loved her very much
and she wanted me to bring you this.
Lía?
My daughter.
Sara used to lend her books.
The poor girl is so upset she didn't
want to come out of the car.
Anyway...
Sorry... Lía would like to know
if Sara left any note.
- We don't know.
- I understand.
Anyway, I won't bother you any longer.
Shall we continue?
Only a neighbour and his daughter?
I didn't know she was so lonely.
But I forgave her.
And I also forgave you.
Now I only need to forgive myself
for not being by her side.
But I did everything I could,
didn't I, Isaac?
The autopsy doesn't reveal
anything strange.
- Have you searched for fingerprints?
- We only found ours and hers.
OK, but...
That song...
And what about what happened
in the cemetery?
Julia, there's no evidence
of anyone being with your sister.
And nobody has seen or heard
anything suspicious.
You can speak with Soledad if you wish.
- With whom?
- An old lady who lives nearby.
Apparently, she helped your sister
when she went blind.
Don't be long.
Where does she live?
Follow the rope in the yard.
What rope?
I'm sure the old woman
doesn't know anything.
Nobody else knew apart from you.
But you have to speak with your wife.
She'll find out sooner or later.
I'll wait for the right moment.
Mrs Soledad?
Hello?
Who is it?
It's Julia, Sara's sister.
I'll be right out.
Sorry about the mess.
The house must be quite disgusting.
Hello...
- Are you there?
- Yes. Sorry, I didn't know you were...
I am sorry too. I wanted to come
to your sister's funeral, but...
it took me an hour to find
a pair of matching shoes.
It's OK.
Were you a good friend of Sara?
Well, when she started
losing her eyesight,
a year ago,
we used to have long conversations.
But lately she hardly spoke with me.
She had made new friends.
- What new friends?
- You know, younger people.
- From the Baumann Centre.
- Baumann Centre. What's that?
A centre for blind people,
not far from here.
One of those places where they make you
believe you can live a normal life.
If you can't hear, you are deaf.
If you lost an arm, you are a cripple.
And if you can't see, you are blind.
And nothing can ever be
how it used to be.
Mrs Soledad, where can I take a taxi?
Thank you.
Go straight ahead,
down the stairs and turn right.
Poor Sara.
- Why would she hang herself?
- Stop thinking about it.
- Shall we have a moment of silence?
- Don't be cruel.
None of us could stand her.
Don't you find it strange?
No.
We've all thought
of doing it at some time.
Dela...
Nora is right. I once thought
of slitting my wrists.
With candles and opera music.
Me too, I thought of jumping
out of the window.
Well, we thought about it
but didn't do it.
There's a reason to live.
Maybe Sara didn't find any.
And a boyfriend doesn't seem like
a good reason?
Sara had a boyfriend?
She told me she met a boy.
- Who?
- No idea.
They had been going out together
for a couple of months.
They even went to Bellavista
together for a week.
- What's in Bellavista?
- Rooms for sex.
Quiet!
How weird! Shit!
What is it?
There's someone here.
- I would say it's Sara.
- That's not funny!
- I can smell her too.
- Something is moving.
- I've got her! Call security!
- I'm Sara's sister.
Julia?
Yes.
- Why were you spying on us?
- I just didn't want to interrupt.
- And who is he?
- Who?
- The man who came with you.
- I came alone.
There's someone else here.
A man, and he's right behind you.
Wait!
Who are you?
Turn around.
I said turn around!
No, no!
Isaac?
Hotel Romeo, Bellavista.
What happened to you?
You are soaking wet.
It started raining
when I left Soledad's house.
Have you been with her all this time?
She invited me for tea.
I couldn't say no.
Julia, I went to look for you.
You left her place an hour ago.
Where have you been?
Why are you so controlling?
I could also ask you
what you're looking for.
Fine.
Now I'm certain there was
something strange in Sara's suicide.
- There's someone watching us.
- Julia, Julia, please.
Who?
Her boyfriend.
- Sara had a boyfriend?
- Yes.
Who told you?
A group of blind girls told me
at the Baumann Centre
and someone was spying on us.
- How do you know?
- Because I ran after him.
- You ran after him?
- Yes, I did.
Isaac.
- Isaac! What are you doing?
- We're leaving this house.
Listen to me. If I have to be
a controlling husband, I will be.
And if I have to drag you out of here,
I will too.
But I won't let you have a seizure.
You know I would never
forgive myself.
Your sister's death has hurt us enough.
You're right.
But I don't feel like
going back home.
Why don't we go somewhere,
you and me, alone?
Where would you like to go?
- Are you sure you want to stay there?
- The guide says it's the cosiest hotel.
Nice view, isn't it?
- Julia.
- Yes, yes. It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Julia...
- I'll park the car.
- Yes, OK.
You don't remember my sister,
a blind woman?
Yes, a colleague talked to me about her.
This may sound weird,
but could you find out
the name of the man who was with her?
- There's no name on the receipt.
- Sorry, but I don't remember any man.
The thing is...
my sister is dead,
and I need to find this man.
Let me see... I don't understand.
Her booking is not registered.
It's as if all the information
was deleted.
- Are you sure?
- Sorry. It must be a computer problem.
You could try El Arlequín. It's the
restaurant we recommend to our guests.
Thank you.
I don't understand how they can
recommend this restaurant.
I like it.
It's not your style at all.
And that waiter
won't stop staring at you.
Really?
- It's your imagination.
- Maybe.
- My reading glasses...
- In your coat? How weird.
I'll go and get them,
and I'll go to the toilet too.
If he hits on you, just yell.
What a change!
I like it. It highlights your eyes.
By the way, I knew they were green.
You're confusing me with my twin sister.
She was here last week.
With her boyfriend.
Her boyfriend?
She came with a man, didn't she?
Yes, I think so.
- Do you remember his name?
- No, no idea.
He was very quiet, very sad.
- Could you describe him?
- Sure, he was...
He was very plain,
like any other man.
But was he tall, short,
blond hair, dark hair?
I can't remember right now.
How can you remember my sister
but nothing about the man?
She drew a bit of attention
with that blindfold.
Blindfold?
She was bandaged after the operation.
- Did she have an operation?
- Of course.
Hence the bet over her eye colour.
She said she'd come
once she'd recovered,
and if I guessed her eye colour,
I could...
- Pablo, can you come for a second?
- Yes, sure.
Excuse me.
My greetings to her.
I couldn't find them.
Let's see how I manage.
Is something wrong?
Sara was here last week.
Julia... what are we doing here?
Isaac, the waiter told me
she had her eyes bandaged.
Do you realise?
If she had the operation and had
a chance to regain her sight,
why would she commit suicide?
Tell me why.
Because the operation didn't work.
What?
It didn't work.
Dr Román told me yesterday.
I was waiting for the right moment
to tell you.
That man exists.
Julia, Julia.
- Anything else I should know?
- I was only trying to protect you.
- From what?
- From the truth.
What's the truth?
Sara committed suicide because
she couldn't stand being blind.
Julia.
Did you know she came here
with her boyfriend?
That doesn't prove anything.
And why is he hiding?
Why didn't he show up at the funeral?
Maybe he wasn't with her by then.
Maybe he left her when he found out
she'd never recover her sight.
That easy?
That easy, right?
- Well...
- I can't believe you're a psychologist.
Julia!
God!
What are you doing?
Julia, Julia.
Didn't you see the car?
You didn't see it, did you?
How many seizures have you had?
Two.
Shit!
Shit.
If...
- If I go blind... When I go blind...
- No, no. That won't happen.
Not wanting it
doesn't mean it won't happen.
Isaac...
One time you told me that...
...when you looked into my eyes,
you could see the entire universe.
- I still can.
- What if the universe shuts down?
Close your eyes.
What?
Can you see me?
Of course I can't.
Then how do you know
I'm still here with you?
Because I can hear you.
What if I remain silent?
How do you know I'm still here?
I can touch you.
And you can smell me.
And kiss you.
Promise me that when the day comes,
we will go back to the desert.
What?
You know?
The last thing I'd like to see
is that sky, with you.
- Julia...
- Promise me.
Promise me.
I promise you.
But...
But you have to promise me...
...that you will stop chasing ghosts.
And that we will go and see Dr Román.
Tomorrow.
OK.
I'll bring the luggage to the car.
I'll wait for you outside.
In 15 minutes.
Ms Levin.
I'm really sorry for your loss.
My name is Créspulo.
I read about your sister
in the obituaries section of the newspaper.
Thank you.
I have something of hers.
A few hours after your sister left,
I found a key in her room,
under the bed.
I think I put it here somewhere.
Thank you.
Mr Créspulo.
I'm sorry.
Mr Créspulo...
My sister came here with a man,
didn't she?
The invisible man.
I beg your pardon?
Nobody remembers the man
who came with your sister, right?
Well...
That doesn't mean he is invisible.
There are people with no light.
Do you know what it's like to walk in
somewhere and not be noticed?
Or to walk on the street
and have people stumble against you?
Or to ask something for the third time
and have no one answer your question?
That's the man you're looking for.
A pause, a vacuum.
An absence.
That's why nobody remembers him.
Nobody except you.
In a way, I am also invisible.
It's been many years since the last time
someone remembered me.
This man...
do you know where I can find him?
What are you afraid of?
He parked his van in a car park
two blocks down the street.
There's a CCTV camera
recording 24 hours a day.
Thank you.
Wait!
Be careful.
The man who was with your sister
had very angry eyes.
He knows how to be a shadow.
If someone feels invisible
and is angry at the world,
he can be dangerous.
He has no light.
Nobody looks at him.
He could sneak up on you and...
- Where have you been?
- Did you see anyone?
- I've been waiting for 10 minutes.
- Wait a moment.
He's here.
And I know how to find him.
- No!
- What are you doing?
- Let me talk to the guard.
- Will you calm down?
- Calm down!
- Wait here.
Don't be so rude!
I remind you
that you made a promise last night.
- Enough.
- I can't take it any more!
- I said don't yell at me!
- I've had it!
There's no mystery in Sara's death!
Do you want the footage?
You'll have it.
But this shit ends
right here, right now, all right?
You've reached...
Excuse me.
Has anyone been here
asking about security videos?
Look... I don't want any trouble, OK?
That guy came, gave me some money
and I promised to keep my mouth shut.
He is my husband.
I've been waiting for a while.
Do you know which way he went out?
He left as soon as my little friend
made the copies he wanted.
And...
Was there anyone else here?
- Are you sure?
- Nobody.
We can check the monitors
in case we see something.
What the hell?
I'll be right back.
Goddammit!
What's wrong?
Calm down. It's me.
Someone has switched off the power.
It's impossible.
My husband has been kidnapped.
He's in danger.
OK, the only thing we know is that
someone stole some CCTV footage.
No, I've already told you.
It was the man who was with my sister.
You have to find him
before it's too late.
How can we find someone
that nobody has seen, not even you?
Créspulo.
- He killed him because he was...
- No evidence of violence.
...the only who could recognise
the invisible man.
- He's erasing his tracks.
- What do you mean?
My husband is in danger!
- Calm down, madam!
- Isaac!
Call a doctor, quick.
We need a doctor down here.
Isaac.
The process is irreversible.
How long do I have?
I don't know...
Perhaps a few hours, days.
Maybe a few weeks.
Definitely less than a month.
We have to find a donor
and operate as soon as possible.
Did you know Sara's boyfriend?
No, I didn't know him.
Julia, I know you're going through
a hard time,
but you have to think about yourself.
So, please,
try to avoid emotional stress.
And don't force your eyes. OK?
Iván. Iván.
A boyfriend?
Sara never told me
about any boyfriends.
She didn't trust men.
Unlike me.
- Or you.
- Isaac hasn't left me, I'm sure.
That's what all women think.
I also came up with a story
when my husband left me.
He couldn't stand my son Ángel.
And my son was more important
than anything else.
Then my eyes started to degenerate
and I went blind.
Luckily, Ángel looked after me
for 10 years,
until I woke up one morning...
and he was gone.
My son was gone.
What kind of son abandons
a blind mother?
I had to come up with a story.
And I still keep to it.
Such humiliation!
I'm sorry.
Hello?
The hotel is fully automated.
There are no staff.
Guests check in through a machine.
They called from the bank this morning
to inform me about a transaction
with your husband's credit card.
I searched the room
and found this on the bedside table.
Julia, there's things about your husband
you don't know.
- He kept Sara's surgery from you.
- To protect me. The doctor told me...
The doctor didn't talk to anybody
about the surgery.
How did your husband know?
Inspector, a patrol just drove by
Sara's house and saw light inside.
Isaac?
Wait here. Don't move.
Hello?
Isaac?
Julia!
Shit! I have to get out of here.
Where is it? Stay calm.
Where is the door? Stay calm.
Julia? Julia?
Inspector! There's somebody
down here. Inspector!
Julia, calm down. It's me.
There's somebody here.
What's wrong?
Turn on the torch.
I hate darkness.
Please, say something.
Why aren't you saying anything?
Thank you.
Hi.
There's something
you should know, Julia.
Your husband left a letter.
We checked the handwriting
and there is no doubt it's his.
Listen...
Sara and Isaac
had been lovers for six months.
He apologises in the letter.
That explains the numerous calls to her
we found on his mobile phone.
Did you know
they were in touch lately?
Think, Julia.
Did Isaac insist on getting the video?
Probably because he didn't want you
to see him on it.
Then he went back to the motel and
decided he couldn't live without Sara.
I'm sorry, but everything makes sense.
We found a donor.
We can operate tomorrow.
You just have to sign here.
Thank you.
Calm down, Julia!
Calm down. Sleep a bit more.
OK, Julia... Everything went well.
But we have to be careful now.
You eyes must be protected
from the light for two weeks.
And don't manipulate
the bandages yourself.
If you remove them too soon,
there won't be a solution.
But don't worry,
you will be taken care of.
No.
I'd rather go home.
I hate hospitals.
I know,
but I'm afraid that's impossible.
- You need supervision.
- I could... go to my sister's house.
I know my way around it very well.
Julia, honestly,
I don't think it's a good idea.
Right, but if I can't see, I can't feel.
All right, let's do this.
You can go to your sister's house.
But a care worker will visit you
every day, OK?
Julia, there's something else.
Your husband's body is still here.
I can take care of it if you want.
No.
I'd rather do it myself.
Could you keep the body
until I can see again?
I need to say goodbye to him.
Let's sit on the sofa. Slowly.
Keep walking...
- Here are your things.
- Thank you.
- Careful. Don't worry.
- No problem.
Shall we wait here
until the care worker arrives?
- Can you do me a favour?
- Sure. What is it?
I'd like to know what this key opens.
Whatever it is this key opens,
it's not here.
- Did you try every lock?
- I did.
Do you need anything else?
No, thank you.
- You can go.
- All right.
- Hello?
- Hi.
You must be Julia.
I'm Iván, the care worker.
Sorry I'm late. The traffic was bad.
I phoned you, but it got cut off.
I would have preferred a woman.
If you want to call Dr Román...
What happened to your hand?
It's just a scratch. You won't
feel anything tomorrow morning.
I will make you dinner
and clean up a bit. You stay here.
By the way...
What should I do with the glasses?
Throw them out.
While you ate,
I familiarised myself with the house.
Julia.
- What are you doing?
- Sorry. I have to go.
What time is it?
It's nine o'clock.
On the first days,
we lose track of time.
I'll give you a couple
of sleeping pills, just in case.
And also a pager.
If you want to contact me,
press this button. Give me your hand.
Look, here's the button.
Let's go.
- What are you doing?
- I have to put you to bed.
- Sorry, but I can do it myself.
- Are you sure?
Are you OK?
OK, you win.
Put me to bed and then you can go.
Who's there?
Calm down.
Calm down, darling.
It's me.
Isaac?
How can this be?
Don't say anything.
Thank you.
- What are you doing?
- Taking this dirty bandage off.
- So you can see me better.
- No!
That's it, that's it.
Leave me alone.
Get off me! Get off me!
Don't resist, little sister.
We're two against one.
Don't move.
No, stop!
Get off me!
Iván. Iván.
Julia, is everything OK?
- I think there's someone in the house.
- What?
In the room next door.
- Don't move. I'll call the police.
- No, Iván, Iván.
Are you still there?
You have to get me out of here
right now.
- Where are you?
- In the guest room.
That's good.
Find the door and get out of the room.
Find the door to your right.
- He's there.
- Calm down.
The handrail is in front of you.
Look for it.
OK, yes.
Hold onto the handrail.
Go down the six steps
to the first landing.
Then there's nine more.
Julia...
- I'm downstairs. What now?
- Follow the wall to the door.
Who are you?
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
Get out of the house! Quick!
There is no indication
that someone entered the house.
There was someone there.
And he was looking for something.
Sorry, but there's nothing else
I can do.
- Do you want me to call the hospital?
- Why?
Maybe you shouldn't recover here,
considering what you've been through.
You don't believe me either.
I'm just saying that in your situation,
it's normal if your senses deceive you.
Don't open your eyes now.
You can let go now.
What's the matter?
My eyes could get damaged, right?
No, I only want to change the bandage,
and I took precautions.
I've done this a hundred times.
Don't worry.
You know, when I was 20 years old,
I had a car accident
and I was blind for two months.
And like you now,
I imagined things and had nightmares.
And I rejected the care worker's help.
I couldn't stand the idea
of going blind.
In the end, I recovered my sight.
But during those months...
...I understood what it was like
to live in the dark.
That's why I became a care worker.
You made that up
to make me feel better.
No, no. Call the hospital
if you don't believe me.
Julia, I know you're scared,
but the only way to lose that fear
is to fight it.
What do you say?
Will you let me help you?
- What happened?
- You spilled it.
Try to get to the door.
Follow the wall with your hand...
And after the glass cabinet...
Well, I have my ups and downs.
But I slept very well
the last few nights.
Iván has been
very patient with me all week.
Yes, he takes good care of me.
I will. I will, yes.
Thanks a lot for calling. Bye.
- Are you leaving?
- Yes. It's a little late.
Why don't stay a bit longer?
A little while.
- Are you still afraid?
- No.
No, it's not that.
Never mind.
OK, should I make
a special dinner for two?
- Go and watch TV. I'll cook.
- That's a little difficult.
Aren't you drinking too much?
I'm celebrating.
What?
That in four days,
I will have the bandages removed
and I will see again.
Everything will be all right, Julia.
You know,
if the operation doesn't work,
I couldn't complain.
I have seen everything I wanted to see.
What's the most beautiful thing
you've ever seen?
Funny!
How ironic that you ask me that.
Why?
Because I spent my whole life
looking for invisible planets.
My eyes have seen amazing things.
But nothing can compare
to the sky in the Sahara.
That's where I met Isaac.
We were on the same excursion
and we spent the whole night...
...staring at the sky.
I asked him, "Is that not the most
beautiful thing you've ever seen?"
And he said, "Yes. "
When I turned my head,
I realised that he'd been watching me
for a while and I got nervous.
And I asked him...
..."Why aren't you watching
the universe?"
And he said,
"I don't have to look up to do it. "
"I can see the universe in your eyes. "
And what happened?
I came close.
I touched him.
And I realised that he was nervous too.
In that moment it was as if
we became one person.
And I wanted to know
if he felt the same.
What did he say?
Nothing.
He replied with his gaze.
Why?
Why did he look at me that way? Why?
- Do you prefer I hadn't done it?
- I don't know.
When you had the affair with Sara,
I thought it was just an indiscretion,
but I swear I don't know
what to think any more.
I don't know what to think.
Everything will be all right, Julia.
You promise?
I promise.
No, I can't.
I can't do it.
It's not right.
- Iván.
- Don't say anything.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be. Don't say anything.
I'll call the hospital
and ask to be replaced.
Is that what you want?
And you?
OK, I'll come back tomorrow and...
If not, just contact me on my pager.
Help! Help!
Help!
Calm down!
I'm Blasco, the neighbour! Lía's father!
Call the police, please!
Calm down!
You need a drink.
No, no.
Call the police, please.
Why do you want to call the police?
To tell another one of your nightmares?
- The last time they didn't believe you.
- No. There was someone by my bed.
I swear, this time it's true.
And what did he want?
To rape you?
It's my daughter.
Don't be afraid.
I told you not to sneak up on people!
Go back to your bed!
And close the door!
Mr Blasco...
Can you call now, please?
Of course, of course.
Don't worry.
How strange.
There's no line.
Calm down.
I'll get the mobile phone.
The mobile is out of battery.
It will take a few minutes to charge.
Sit down, sit down.
Sit down.
What do you say?
Do you want something to drink
while we wait?
- What do you say?
- Could I have a glass of water?
- Water?
- Yes, my throat is a bit dry.
Julia, where are you going?
Hey!
Madam!
Where are you, madam?
Please, pick up.
Iván.
Pick up, please.
Julia, what's wrong?
- Julia!
- Iván!
- Let's go to your house.
- Not my house.
- Julia, calm down.
- No, my house is not safe.
Please. Take me to your place.
OK.
OK, thanks. Bye.
What did they say?
Inspector Dimas
won't be on duty until seven.
You should get some rest
and I'll go with you tomorrow morning.
Julia, I won't let anyone hurt you.
You can sleep in my bed.
- And you?
- I have a mattress. I'll be right back.
- No, no.
- I'll be right back. You're safe here.
I'll be back in a minute.
Iván?
- Who are you?
- I'm Lía.
- Lía Blasco.
Don't get close.
How did you find me?
- I followed you. I was Sara's friend.
- I said don't come close.
Listen, my father
has nothing to do with all this.
- Your father lied to me.
- My father is lonely, and you're hot.
I don't believe you.
I was the one who took the key
and have been spying on you.
- You?
- Do you have nightmares?
- What?
- Sara also had them.
She dreamt of someone taking the bandage
off and piercing her eyes with needles.
There's a monster on the street,
but no one can see him
because he hides in the darkness.
He made Sara go blind
and will do the same with you.
- Stop!
- It's him.
I followed him and tried the key.
And today I saw the needles again.
- It's him, Julia. It's the care worker.
- No.
Listen to me!
Do you really think Isaac
killed himself? He loved you.
- He loved Sara more.
- They didn't want to worry you.
That's why they kept you in the dark.
Sara told me.
Isaac wrote a suicide note.
Leave me alone.
- The monster forced him to write it.
- Monsters don't exist. Enough!
This one does.
He collects pictures.
His wall is covered
with pictures of you and Sara.
- He removed your eyes.
- Lía, that's enough!
Leave me alone!
What are you doing?
Use the key if you don't believe me.
The key. Where's the key?
- He took it.
- No, you took it.
- Why me?
- I don't know. To protect your father.
- It's him. Don't tell him I'm here.
- Lía. Lía.
Iván?
Julia, what are you doing?
I'm really nervous.
I'll make you a cup of tea.
It will help you relax.
- Iván...
- Yes?
I can't find the key. It's the only
evidence to incriminate Blasco.
Did you take it?
- You must have dropped it.
- Please, give it to me.
I'll keep it for you.
You are very nervous.
I'll make you a cup of tea.
You sit down and relax.
He's lying. He had the key.
- We have to get out of here.
- I don't want to.
- You don't believe me now?
- It's impossible. He is a care worker.
Shit! It's locked.
- Julia!
- Yes?
- Do you want sugar?
- Two teaspoons, thanks.
He wants to drug you and make you blind.
What are you saying?
- Can you take this off?
- No. Why?
Then we can't get out of the window.
I need to get the key.
Get rid of him
and wait for me in the bathroom.
Here you go.
I'll take you to bed
and wait until you fall asleep.
I need to go to the bathroom.
OK.
Thank you.
- Julia, is everything all right?
- Yes. What was that noise?
I don't know. I heard it too.
I thought something had happened to you.
- Hurry up, or your tea will get cold.
- I'll be right out.
Lía, please.
Four days left. Only four days.
Four days, four days.
Julia, I have to go down again.
Are you OK?
Yes, I'll be right out.
Lía.
What are you doing here?
Why are you crying?
Please, answer me.
A girl called Lía came to see me.
Blasco's daughter.
And she made me very nervous.
- Why did you take the bandage off?
- I couldn't see anything.
She told me horrible things about you
and I was afraid.
About me?
You would never hurt me, would you?
No.
I had to...
I had to see your face to know it.
And what did you see?
Nothing. I can't see anything.
Are you sure you can't see anything?
Sometimes the eyes
take time to adjust.
The operation didn't work.
I'm really sorry, Julia.
Probably the girl lied to you
in order to protect her father.
Tomorrow... we'll speak with
the inspector and all this will be over.
No. No.
No, please.
Take me to the hospital now.
- Now, please.
- We'll call Dr Román.
- Now.
- Julia, listen to me.
Dr Román?
It's Iván. Sorry to wake you
at this time of night.
I have a problem with Julia Levin.
She took the bandage off by accident.
I understand. I will tell her right now.
Thanks, and sorry to bother you.
What did he say?
He's at a conference.
We can't do anything until next week.
- Then take me to a different hospital.
- No. Román said you have to rest.
- I need a second opinion.
- Julia, the damage is done.
But if you don't do as I say,
it will be irreversible.
OK.
Why did you get up?
- The kettle was whistling.
- I'll do it. You sit down.
Be careful.
Very good.
This is nearly ready.
Here you are.
Thank you.
What's the matter?
Why are you doing all this, Iván?
What do you mean?
Why all this attention?
What do you want from me?
Well, Julia...
When...
When you kissed me...
I didn't expect it.
I didn't expect it, but don't think
I don't like you because...
because that's not true.
I only wanted to give you some time.
You've suffered a lot.
And some wounds need to heal.
What I'm trying to say is...
...I want to be with you.
Drink your tea.
Did you put sugar in it?
I'll bring some.
Two teaspoons, right?
As usual.
Done?
Can you come with me, please?
- Why?
- I need your help with the freezer.
Come. Let's go. Leave this here.
Open the freezer.
Why?
Just do it.
Open the freezer, I said.
Liar.
Are you afraid?
You don't know what fear is!
You have no idea what fear is!
Real fear.
Fear of being ignored and rejected.
Look at me. Look at me!
You don't know what it's like to live
in the dark and hide in another world.
A world full of silence,
getting used to measuring your steps.
Always wearing
the appropriate clothes.
Making your voice one voice and none.
And your eyes, two eyes and none.
It takes so long that eventually
you become a shadow.
But one day you find out that
blind girls realise that you're there,
that you're breathing,
that you are still alive.
That you can offer them your eyes
for theirs, your hands for theirs...
That's why our relationship
is so perfect.
That's why...
...we have to continue this way.
If you are not Iván, who are you?
Where are you taking me?
My eyes hurt.
Something is wrong.
Take the bandage off, please.
Please.
Please, take it off.
Please, my eyes hurt.
Take the bandage off.
Shut up!
I beg you.
Let me see.
It's started again, right?
This time...
...it will be more intense.
Get out of the car.
You have to pack your bags.
Open the door, Julia.
Open the fucking door!
Open the door!
Julia!
Who's there?
Is the main door locked?
- Is that you, Julia? You scared me.
- Is it locked?
Yes, of course.
What's wrong?
- There's a murderer in the area.
- A murderer?
We have to call the police.
Where's the phone?
There, in the corner.
Under the painting.
Don't move.
Be quiet.
- What's wrong?
- Don't move.
- It's him. He's here.
- Who?
Don't come any closer,
you son of a bitch.
- Who are you talking to?
- To a man who thinks he's invisible.
He made Sara go blind
and he wants to do the same to me.
- You're scaring me.
- Stay away.
Soledad, call the police.
- Call the police, quick!
- Don't do it, Mum.
Ángel...
Is that you, son?
Yes.
I'm back home.
This woman says you're chasing her.
This woman is crazy.
- Your son is a murderer.
- Shut up. Don't listen to her, Mum.
- He killed my husband.
- She's lying.
- He killed my husband and Sara too.
- Shut up.
- It must have been easy to hang her.
- I loved Sara.
She killed herself because she wasn't
capable of living in darkness.
Capable?
No one is capable of getting used to it.
You made her go blind.
You killed her.
- Is that true, son?
- Mum, mum. You know me.
I said don't move.
Make the call. Make it.
I knew you'd come back.
I knew you'd realise
that you can only be happy here.
I told you that without me,
you'd be nothing.
Less than nothing.
Invisible.
Since when can you see, Mum?
But you're still my son, and I won't let
anybody take you away from me.
Mum, I asked you a question.
Since when can you see?
Ángel, what are you doing, son?
What are you doing, son? No, no.
No, no.
Calm down, Mum.
- It's me.
- Mum, calm down.
Look, Mum, this liquid attacks the optic
nerve without causing any pain.
Don't worry.
And these needles are very useful too.
- Don't do it, please.
- Mum, I have to do it.
- Oh, my boy!
- Don't worry.
What are we doing here?
I won't use it on you.
Your optic nerve must be very damaged
by now. It won't take long.
- This can't end like this.
- Don't worry. Don't worry.
Don't worry. When the darkness comes,
I'll be by your side.
I've packed your bags.
We will go far away
and nobody will find us.
We will start from scratch.
Don't touch me!
Don't touch me, son of a bitch.
I will never love you. Never.
I would die first.
- Don't touch me!
- Is that what you want?
Don't touch me!
Let go of me!
- Let go of me!
- Come on, do it!
Stay with me.
Do it. Do it.
Do it! Do it!
- Do it.
- I can't! I can't!
Of course you can't.
Although you don't know it...
you love me.
Because you know that without me,
you are nothing.
And I am only a shadow without you.
Julia, why did you lock the door?
- Hello?
- Inspector. It's Julia.
Julia, it's you.
Listen to me, because this is
the last time I'll call you.
- Calm down.
- He's locked me in my house.
- Calm down, Julia.
- He's going to kill me.
If you don't come, it will be too late.
You have to believe me. Please.
- Julia, please, calm down.
- Are you listening to me?
Inspector?
Julia!
Julia, police!
Cover the stairs and the hallway.
Julia, are you there?
It's Dimas. Can you hear me?
- Julia, what are you doing?
- Shut up!
- What's going on?
- I said shut up!
Can you see him?
Can you see him, Inspector?
Police! Put the knife down!
Put your hands above your head!
Don't look at me.
Don't look at me, please.
- Don't look at me!
- Put the knife down!
Put it down!
What are you doing?
Put the knife down!
I will go blind, won't I?
How long do I have?
You'll go blind before dawn.
I need you to do me a favour.
Can we have a moment?
What happened to his eyes?
He donated them.
And where are they?
Where he would have wanted.
Isaac, why?
My God, I miss you so much.
You promised me.
You told me
that when you looked into my eyes...
...you could see the entire universe.
I still can.
JULIA'S EYES